Sumit Ghewade

FORMER INTERN UI ENGINEER AT SAP LABS | FORMER SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT LARSEN & TOUBRO INFOTECH

ghewadesumit@gmail.com | 513-592-7247 | https://github.com/ghewadesumit | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sumit-ghewade

Summary

Master's Student in Computer Science with **3 years** of professional work experience in Software Engineering, Web Development. An enthusiastic software developer and an avid learner with expertise in ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (ES6).

Education

University of Cincinnati, Ohio | MASTER'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Pune, India | BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug2018 - April 2020

Jan 2011 - May 2015

Technical Skills

JavaScript (ES6) | TypeScript | ReactJS | React Hooks | Redux | NodeJS | ExpressJS | GraphQL | Enzymes | YARN | NPM | WebPack | MySQL | MongoDB | Mongoose | HTML | CSS3 | SASS | Bootstrap3 | XML | JSON | Python | Java | AJAX | OData | AWS | Docker | Restful Web services | Postman | Git | Scrum | Agile Methodology | Data Structures and Algorithms

Online Courses: Modern JavaScript, HTML CSS & JavaScript Build 6 Projects, CSS Bootcamp, MERN, React & Redux, Python

Experience

Ernst & Young LLP | Front End Engineer | Hoboken, New Jersey

Jan 2021 - Current

- Worked on the Chat Bot application in the Health Care sector, which will help the patients to book appointment with doctor.
- Implemented the User Interface for the chat bot application. Made it responsive to fit almost all screen sizes.
- Application supported all the major browsers from Mozilla, Safari, Chrome, Edge, Internet Explorer.
- Followed Accessibility standards and design guidelines to facilitate all types of users.
- Implemented eslinting to have a standard development of the application.
- Helped in standardizing the Ungork In house Training Material and Trained colleagues & clients on Ungork Technology.

SAP LABS | INTERN UI ENGINEER | Palo Alto, California

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

Requirement Gathering Tool | Typescript, NodeJS, ReactJS, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, Enzymes, HTML5, Agile, CSS/ SASS, Github

- Requirement Gathering tool is a Visual Studio Code extension that helps accelerate development of the SAP ERP application.
- Built 60% of reusable responsive components such as custom buttons, message toast, Dialog Box, and collapsible side panels.
- Created GraphQL schemas and Implemented API endpoints to handle CRUD operations along with duplicate operation.
- Implemented Unit testing modules using Jest, Enzyme for react components to make application development process robust.

Larsen & Toubro Infotech | SOFTWARE ENGINEER | Pune, India

Aug 2015 - Feb 2018

Smart Analyzer | JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap3

- Implemented UI and functions for converting more than 70 CSV files with diverse internal structure into a JSON file.
- Automated the report to check for errors in the CSV files. Delivered the JSON file, minimizing the file size up to 50-60%.

Fuel Competency Management Service (FCMS) | Web Dynpro Java, Java, OData, AJAX, JavaScript, HTML5, Bootstrap3, XML, MySQL

- Migrated application portal information and processes to more efficient solutions.
- Implemented REST/OData services to connect the EJB code to frontend on SAP HANA.
- Generated compact reports at 80% less time than the previous portal applications.
- Integrated 8 distinct applications for successful completion of any end-to-end transaction process.

Projects

DevConnector Application | MongoDB, React.js, Express.js, Node.js

University of Cincinnati

- DevConnector is a professional platform where developers can post articles and other users can comment on the post.
- Backend is implemented using ExpressJs, implemented a middleware that creates a unique JWT token when the user logs in, to remember the user until the token expires, to make the application stateful.
- Request to the server and response from the server were handled in Redux Actions using Axios.
- Based on the received response in Redux Action, it was directed to the appropriate reducer.

E-commerce Application [React.js, Redux, JavaScript, NodeJs, Express.js, Firebase, CSS/ SASS

University of Cincinnati

- Developed and maintained components of e-commerce application, like shopping cart, checkout page, and category page.
- Used Firebase to store the new user sign-in information and used Gmail authentication to quickly sign-up users.

Eight Responsive Front-End Projects | JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

University of Cincinnati

- Developed six responsive web applications, the application are Invisible Card, Custom Sign-up Form, Profile-Card, Slideshow, Ham-Burger Menu, Tic-Tac-Toe, Monster Search and 3D-Cube.
- *Furniture Store* application was developed to learn and implement the concept of Grid Layout and *Grand Hotel* application was developed to learn and implement the concept of Flexbox.